moneyto.co.uk 2019-02-02

# Privacy Policy | Send Money with MoneyTO

### Our Privacy Commitment

This privacy policy sets out how Moneyto Ltd uses and protects any information that you give Moneyto Ltd when you use this website. The policy is compliant with the [GDPR](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr).

Moneyto Ltd is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. Moneyto Ltd may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. We will inform you by a privacy notice of any changes of this policy. This policy is effective from 25th May 2018

Any dispute or claim arising in connection with this Privacy Policy will be considered in relation to the English version only.

### Personal identification infromation

The types of personal information we collect depends on the products or services you have requested from us.

Generally, personal information is collected from you on transaction forms, or at our websites, when you request our products or services, manage your online account, dashboards, or enroll in the Moneyto Ltd Program or manage your account(s) and preferences. We may also collect information about you from third-party reference sources, vendors, and clearinghouse services as part of our verification processes or otherwise in connection with your use of our products or services.

We collect your personal information directly from you and/or from the party on the other side of your transaction, for example, when you tell us where to send money or who should receive the money; give us your contact information; or In addition, depending on the services requested and/or the amount of your money transfer, Moneyto Ltd may also collect and may disclose personal and non-personal information, such as date of birth, National insurance number or other identifying number (including type, issuer, and expiration date) and any other information necessary to verify and process the request. The debit card data is collected only in payment process execution purposes and we’re not keeping payment information in our database.

### What we do with the information we gather

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * Internal record keeping.
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.
  * We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.
  * Otherwise with consent or as permitted or required by applicable law. Personal information will be subject to the laws of the country in which it is located including lawful access requests by government authorities. The laws of these countries (which may include countries outside the European Economic Area) may not have similar data protection laws to the European Economic Area.
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone or mail. We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests.

### Use of Information Collected

We may disclose the information that we collect, as described above, with Service Providers acting on our behalf to provide online financial services.

  * We may also disclose Customer Information when required or permitted by law. For example, Customer Information may be disclosed in connection with a subpoena or similar legal process, fraud prevention, or security investigation. If you will be affected of any fraud that cause to you any financial loss, or loss of your reputation we will inform you straight away.
  * We may also disclose aggregate (not personally identifiable) Customer Information with Service Providers or financial institutions that perform marketing and research services on our behalf and with whom we have joint marketing agreements. Our contracts require all such Service Providers/or financial institutions to protect the confidentiality of your Customer Information to the same extent that we must do.
  * We do not disclose any Customer Information about our customers, former customers, website visitors to anyone, except as permitted or required by law.
  * We do not sell any of your personal information.

### Security

We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Policy. We implement technical and organisation measures to protect your Personal Data and follow data retention practices in line with applicable law.

**Sensitive and private data exchange between the Site and its Users happens over a SSL secured communication channel and is encrypted and protected.**

### Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [info@moneyto.co.uk](mailto:info@moneyto.co.uk)

### Cookies

Our Website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our Website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our Website and also allows us to improve our Website. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them see our Cookie Policy.

### Your rights

You have the right to:

  * Request information about whether we hold personal information about you, and, if so, what that information is and why we are holding/using it.
  * Request access to your personal information (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal information we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
  * Request correction of the personal information that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate information we hold about you corrected.
  * Request erasure of your personal information. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal information where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal information where you have exercised your right to object to processing (see below).
  * Object to processing of your personal information where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal information for direct marketing purposes.
  * Object to automated decision-making including profiling, that is not to be subject of any automated decision-making by us using your personal information or profiling of you.
  * Request the restriction of processing of your personal information. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of personal information about you, for example if you want us to establish its accuracy or the reason for processing it.
  * Request transfer of your personal information in an electronic and structured form to you or to another party (commonly known as a right to “data portability”). This enables you to take your data from us in an electronically useable format and to be able to transfer your data to another party in an electronically useable format.
  * Withdraw consent. In the limited circumstances where you may have provided your consent to the collection, processing and transfer of your personal information for a specific purpose, you have the right to withdraw your consent for that specific processing at any time. Once we have received notification that you have withdrawn your consent, we will no longer process your information for the purpose or purposes you originally agreed to, unless we have another legitimate basis for doing so in law.

If you want to exercise any of these rights, please contact us on email at [info@moneyto.co.uk](mailto:info@moneyto.co.uk) or by post at 91-95 Newington butts, London, United Kingdom, SE1 6SF.

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal information (or to exercise any of the other rights). We will also comply with any reasonable request within 30 days However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request for access is clearly unfounded or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with the request in such circumstances.

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access the information (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is another appropriate security measure to ensure that personal information is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it.

Should you be dissatisfied with our response to your data subject access request, or any actions or processes we have conducted in terms of your personal data, you have the right to complain to the [Information Commissioners Office (ICO)](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/) at ico.org.uk.

However in the first instance you should report your concerns to us. A helpful format for such a complaint can also be found on the ICO website at ico.org.uk.

### How long do we keep your data?

We will only hold your data as long as necessary to serve the purpose it is used for, what time is depending on what purpose your data is used for.

Regulatory:

We are required by law to keep the data obtained from you (KYC, CDD, transaction records) for at least 5 years from the most recent transaction, please see Part 4 of [MLR 2017](https://www.legislation.gov.uk/uksi/2017/692/pdfs/uksi_20170692_en.pdf).

Legitimate Interest:

Once the five years of retention period and/or the legitimate interest no longer apply, we will remove your data from our system.

### Consent

If you give us specific consent to process certain kinds of data, you are able to withdraw that consent at any time by log into your personal account, or by writing to us at [info@moneyto.co.uk](mailto:info@moneyto.co.uk). We will then stop processing your data and, if the five years retention and/or legitimate interest period does not apply we will also erase your data from our system.

We may retain any data mentioned above for a longer period, if required to protect the rights, property or safety of Moneyto Limited or of the services provided by us or our partners.

### Contact us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us at:

Phone:

  * +44(0)2077032136 (Spanish/English)
  * +44(0)2085197987 (Russian/English)

E-mail: [info@moneyto.co.uk](mailto:info@moneyto.co.uk)
